<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pixodius</title>
    <link>/authors/nazim/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/nazim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Pixodius</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Nazimur Rahiman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Pixodius</title>
      <link>/authors/nazim/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running is good for you!</title>
      <link>/blog/garfield-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/garfield-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best Garfield comic strip!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virgin MVR-02</title>
      <link>/blog/virgin-mvr-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/virgin-mvr-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shot at Singapore Grand Prix in 2011 using a Nikon D60 and Nikon AF-S DX VR Nikkor 55-300mm f/4.5-5.6G ED lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;EXIF:
195mm ƒ/5.3 1/40s ISO 200
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virgin-mvr-02&#34;&gt;Virgin MVR-02&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Virgin MVR-02 is a Formula One racing car designed by Wirth Research for Marussia Virgin Racing, and used by them during the 2011 Formula One season. Like its predecessor, the Virgin VR-01, the MVR-02 was designed entirely with computational fluid dynamics, with Nick Wirth’s design studio doubling their CFD capacity ahead of the 2011 season. The addition of the “M” in the car’s chassis designation reflected the team’s new owner, Russian sports car manufacturer Marussia Motors. The car was unveiled in London on 7 February 2011, and was driven during the racing season by returning driver Timo Glock and debutant Jérôme d’Ambrosio. - Wiki&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-a-copy-on-getty-images&#34;&gt;Buy a copy on Getty Images:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;getty embed image &#34; style=&#34;background-color:#fff;display:inline-block;font-family:Roboto,sans-serif;color:#a7a7a7;font-size:11px;width:100%;max-width:554px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:0;margin:0;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gettyimages.com.au/detail/979176224&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;color:#a7a7a7;text-decoration:none;font-weight:normal !important;border:none;display:inline-block;&#34;&gt;Embed from Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;overflow:hidden;position:relative;height:0;padding:56.137188% 0 0 0;width:100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;//embed.gettyimages.com/embed/979176224?et=tQyoFJiTSJZDKqNsT8PnDA&amp;tld=com.au&amp;sig=cvh3le2Wo2GlnAg3XVoXDDUKEsihbBY6UoAE2cAFUoY=&amp;caption=false&amp;ver=1&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;554&#34; height=&#34;311&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raymond&#39;s Tomb</title>
      <link>/blog/raymonds-tomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/raymonds-tomb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyderabad is known for its rich history, culture and architecture representing its unique character as a meeting point for North and South India, and also its multicultural nature, geographically, culturally and intellectually. Also known as The City of Nizams and The City of Pearls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;michel-joachim-marie-raymonds-tomb&#34;&gt;Michel Joachim Marie Raymond’s Tomb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20-year-old Michel Raymond left France in 1775 for the Indian shores to become a merchant like his father, but Fate had other plans for him. He joined the French forces in Pondicherry in fighting the British. Their on-and-off skirmishes and Raymond’s role in the French victories brought him into the notice of the Nizam of Hyderabad. He joined the Nizam’s forces in 1786; a step that was to establish and cement his bonds with Hyderabad and its people, and become a part of its lore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He rose in the ranks rapidly and became a trusted aide of the Nizam, to the extent that a “Gora” was given the crucial position of Amin Jinsi or Comptroller of Ordinance. Once he assumed charge, he revolutionized the artillery of the army and established the Gun foundry, which still stands today as a testimony to his vision. Under his guidance, the Nizam’s army became one of the best fortified and most formidable in the entire region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle was in his blood, but there was more to this man than just the art of war. Raymond was known far and wide as a good, kind man who never looked down upon the local populace unlike many other foreigners. His bravery, contribution to Hyderabad and his loyalty to the Nizam won him many epithets - to the Muslims he was Musa Rahim, and to the Hindus he was Musa Ram (whence the name Musarambagh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise that when this foreigner died in 1798 at the young age of 43, he was deeply mourned by all. His dear friend the Nizam had a special memorial errected for him on the top of a hillock, and it still stands there today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tomb is a black granite obelisk, and it has the initials JR on it. At the foot of the tomb lies a Grecian-styled pavilion, which is said to house the graves of his family. At the bottom of the hill lies another obelisk which was built over the remains of Raymond’s faithful dog and horse. Even in his death, the people of Hyderabad saw to it that he was surrounded by those he loved and who had loved him back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The years have not been kind to Raymond’s memories, with a handful of people knowing the location of the tomb and the stature of the man interred therein. The dilapidated tomb was rebuilt in April 2003, and an open-air theater around the Grecian pavilion was also constructed. And the tomb is still used as a venue for qawwali evenings held in his memory every year. But what you find when you go there today is weeds, graffiti and a sense of desolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monogrammed tomb has a thin trickle of visitors, even after the renovation. The few people who do find their way there usually spend more time gazing into the panoramic view of Hyderabad that the hill affords. A cursory glance at the tomb and a few sniff of disdain about the disarray is what Raymond has been reduced to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of Michel Raymond stands to become lost to the people of today unless it is retold. Here lies a man who was a saint of sorts to the locals. A lesser known one albeit, but a well-loved one nonetheless. He stands testimony to Hyderabad’s multihued culture, and to the friendliness of the locals who took a stranger from a far-off land into their hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; fullhyd.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    How to get there: Going from Malakpet, at the Asmangarh Signals, where the left goes to Amberpet - take a right and go into the lane next to Hotel Sham. The road is steep and climbs crazily, go all the way up and come down the other side. At the bottom of the hill take a left and proceed some 400 mts. Finally you will find a faded grey board pointing to a lane - the Mons Raymond Monument is at the end of that lane lined with houses.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the Locals at Moosarambagh area knew about the existence of this tomb! This is the only board which we found. (We got the location after speaking to a policeman at the Malakpet station)





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-jzjqVLB-L.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-jzjqVLB-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-this-one-picture-is-sufficient-to-prove-the-state-of-maintenance-here&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-5fLTMfv-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;This one picture is sufficient to prove the state of maintenance here!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-5fLTMfv-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    This one picture is sufficient to prove the state of maintenance here!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of this passage, there are encroachments/huts and people are living inside the walls of a Protected monument!





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-jdsxpjH-L.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-jdsxpjH-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-and-heres-the-proof&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-zbfSd8d-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;And here&amp;rsquo;s the proof&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-zbfSd8d-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    And here&amp;rsquo;s the proof
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;raymonds-sisters-tomb&#34;&gt;Raymond&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s tomb&lt;/h3&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-4PnfbQC-L.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-4PnfbQC-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-brief-history&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-9hsLPJH-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;A brief history&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-9hsLPJH-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    A brief history
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-b4wGffJ-L.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-b4wGffJ-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;raymonds-tomb&#34;&gt;Raymond&amp;rsquo;s Tomb&lt;/h3&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-zNnJHTT-L.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-zNnJHTT-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-jr-written-on-the-tomb&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-PgnSv3h-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;J.R Written on the tomb&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-PgnSv3h-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    J.R Written on the tomb
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rebuilt 28-pillared open structure resembling a Grecian Temple. The caretaker was very knowledgeable and was expressing his helplessness in protecting the monument.





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-QWWvHWJ-L.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-QWWvHWJ-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-view-from-the-hillock&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-Wmvwgrz-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;View from the hillock&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-Wmvwgrz-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    View from the hillock
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tv-tower-as-seen-from-the-tomb&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-c2pTRHN-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;TV Tower as seen from the tomb&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-c2pTRHN-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    TV Tower as seen from the tomb
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-yellow-building-in-the-center-is-the-asmangadh-palace&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-ZMgjqJ4-L.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The yellow building in the center is the AsmanGadh Palace&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/raymonds_tomb/i-ZMgjqJ4-L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The yellow building in the center is the AsmanGadh Palace
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
