<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General | Nazim</title>
    <link>/tags/general/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>General</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Nazimur Rahiman - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:square]</url>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>/tags/general/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pale Blue Dot</title>
      <link>/blog/pale-blue-dot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pale-blue-dot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Pale Blue Dot&lt;/strong&gt; is a photograph of planet Earth taken in 1990 by the &lt;strong&gt;Voyager 1&lt;/strong&gt; spaceprobe from a record distance of about &lt;strong&gt;6 billion kilometers (3.7 billion miles, 40 AU)&lt;/strong&gt; from Earth, as part of the solar system Family Portrait series of images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the photograph, Earth is shown as a fraction of a pixel (0.12 pixel in size) against the vastness of space. The Voyager 1 spacecraft, which had completed its primary mission and was leaving the Solar System, was commanded by NASA to turn its camera around and to take a photograph of Earth across a great expanse of space, at the request of &lt;strong&gt;Carl Sagan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this distant vantage point, the Earth might not seem of any particular interest. But for us, it’s different. Consider again that dot. That’s here. That’s home. That’s us. On it everyone you love, everyone you know, everyone you ever heard of, every human being who ever was, lived out their lives. The aggregate of our joy and suffering, thousands of confident religions, ideologies, and economic doctrines, every hunter and forager, every hero and coward, every creator and destroyer of civilization, every king and peasant, every young couple in love, every mother and father, hopeful child, inventor and explorer, every teacher of morals, every corrupt politician, every “superstar,” every “supreme leader,” every saint and sinner in the history of our species lived there – &lt;em&gt;on a mote of dust suspended in a sunbeam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Image Credits: Wikimedia Commons
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
